{
    "quizData": [
        {
            "id": "0",
            "question": "Which is the most widely spoken language in the world?",
            "options": [
                "Spanish",
                "Mandarin",
                "English",
                "German"
            ],
            "correct": "Mandarin"
        },
        {
            "id": "1",
            "question": "Which is the only continent in the world without a desert?",
            "options": [
                "North America",
                "Asia",
                "Africa",
                "Europe"
            ],
            "correct": "Europe"
        },
        {
            "id": "2",
            "question": "Who invented Computer?",
            "options": [
                "Charles Babbage",
                "Henry Luce",
                "Henry Babbage",
                "Charles Luce"
            ],
            "correct": "Charles Babbage"
        },
        {
            "id": "3",
            "question": "Alongside former President Frederik Willem de Klerk, which then President of South Africa won a Nobel prize for their work to peacefully end apartheid in the country?",
            "options": [
                "Mgabe",
                "Henry Gbague",
                "Nelson Mandela",
                "Luke Mooore"
            ],
            "correct": "Nelson Mandela"
        },
        {
            "id": "4",
            "question": "How many cards are there in a pack of cards (not incl. jokers)?",
            "options": [
                "52",
                "53",
                "50",
                "32"
            ],
            "correct": "52"
        },
        {
            "id": "5",
            "question": "What does www stand for?",
            "options": [
                "World wide web",
                "West Wide World",
                "Wide wide west",
                "Web Wide World"
            ],
            "correct": "World wide web"
        },
        {
            "id": "6",
            "question": "Where might you find Tower Bridge and Buckingham Palace, amongst many other landmarks?",
            "options": [
                "Canada",
                "London",
                "Paris",
                "USA"
            ],
            "correct": "London"
        },
        {
            "id": "7",
            "question": "What is the name of Mickey Mouse’s partner?",
            "options": [
                "Minnie Mouse",
                "Mouse",
                "Nicky Mouse",
                "Nicky"
            ],
            "correct": "Minnie Mouse"
        },
        {
            "id": "8",
            "question": "What country is famous for inventing the Taco, Burrito and Quesadilla?",
            "options": [
                "Italy",
                "Spain",
                "Mexico",
                "France"
            ],
            "correct": "Mexico"
        },
        {
            "id": "9",
            "question": "Who is the South African born CEO of SpaceX and the brains behind Tesla?",
            "options": [
                "Mark Zukerberg",
                "Elon Musk",
                "Jeff Bezos",
                "Ma"
            ],
            "correct": "Elon Musk"
        },
        {
            "id": "10",
            "question": "What animal is Pumbaa in the Lion King?",
            "options": [
                "A Lion",
                "A Zebra",
                "A Lioness",
                "A warthog"
            ],
            "correct": "A warthog"
        },
        {
            "id": "11",
            "question": "What company is responsible for the iPhone, iPad and iWatch and many other products?",
            "options": [
                "Apple",
                "Andriod",
                "HTC",
                "XOS"
            ],
            "correct": "Apple"
        },
        {
            "id": "12",
            "question": "What is the largest country by area in the world?",
            "options": [
                "Russia",
                "USA",
                "India",
                "China"
            ],
            "correct": "Russia"
        },
        {
            "id": "13",
            "question": "In which country would you find Angel Falls, the highest waterfall on earth?",
            "options": [
                "Cameroon",
                "Venezuela",
                "South Africa",
                "Columbia"
            ],
            "correct": "Venezuela"
        },
        {
            "id": "14",
            "question": "What city is the capital of France?",
            "options": [
                "Lyon",
                "Troyes",
                "Paris",
                "Lile"
            ],
            "correct": "Paris"
        },
        {
            "id": "15",
            "question": "How many states are there in America? ",
            "options": [
                "49",
                "50",
                "51",
                "52"
            ],
            "correct": "50"
        },
        {
            "id": "16",
            "question": "Name the capital of China.",
            "options": [
                "Beijing",
                "Chou Zhoua",
                "Goan",
                "Lie jung"
            ],
            "correct": "Beijing"
        },
        {
            "id": "17",
            "question": "Which is larger the Pacific or the Atlantic Ocean?",
            "options": [
                "Pacific",
                "Atlantic Ocean",
                "None",
                "Both"
            ],
            "correct": "Pacific"
        },
        {
            "id": "18",
            "question": "Who was assassinated, leading to the start of the First World War?",
            "options": [
                "Granz Murphy",
                "Archduke Franz Ferdinand",
                "Duke Ferdinando",
                "Adolf Hitler"
            ],
            "correct": "Archduke Franz Ferdinand"
        },
        {
            "id": "19",
            "question": "Who conquered England in 1066?",
            "options": [
                "William (the Conqueror)",
                "James (the Conqueror)",
                "Jacob (the Conqueror)",
                "Harry (the Conqueror)"
            ],
            "correct": "William (the Conqueror)"
        },
        {
            "id": "20",
            "question": "In what year did the US sign the declaration of Independence, now celebrated on 4th July each year?",
            "options": [
                "1776",
                "1786",
                "1796",
                "1806"
            ],
            "correct": "1776"
        },
        {
            "id": "21",
            "question": "Where was the famous attack by Japan that led to America joining World War II?",
            "options": [
                "Pearl Harbor",
                "Duke Harlum",
                "David West",
                "Jack Zukhi"
            ],
            "correct": "Pearl Harbor"
        },
        {
            "id": "22",
            "question": "Which British King famously had six wives?",
            "options": [
                "Henry VIII",
                "Harry VIII",
                "Ryan VIII",
                "Justin VIII"
            ],
            "correct": "Henry VIII"
        },
        {
            "id": "23",
            "question": "In which city was Jesus said to have been born?",
            "options": [
                "Bneiu Yehuda",
                "Cairo",
                "Jarusalem",
                "Bethlehem"
            ],
            "correct": "Bethlehem"
        },
        {
            "id": "24",
            "question": "What is the most played sport in India and has produced many greats of the game including Sachin Tendulkar and Sunil Gavaskar?",
            "options": [
                "Cricket",
                "Soccer",
                "Tennis",
                "Dancing"
            ],
            "correct": "Cricket"
        },
        {
            "id": "25",
            "question": "The All Blacks are the rugby team of which country?",
            "options": [
                "USA",
                "London",
                "France",
                "New Zealand"
            ],
            "correct": "New Zealand"
        },
        {
            "id": "26",
            "question": "Which English footballer retired in 2006 with a record 260 Premiership goals?",
            "options": [
                "Wayne Rooney",
                "Ryan Gigs",
                "Alan Shearer",
                "Fletcher"
            ],
            "correct": "Alan Shearer"
        },
        {
            "id": "27",
            "question": "Which basketball team became the first to reach the milestone of 3,000 wins in 2010?",
            "options": [
                "Chicago Bulls",
                "LA Lakers",
                "NY Bulls",
                "Eagles"
            ],
            "correct": "LA Lakers"
        },
        {
            "id": "28",
            "question": "Dubbed the ‘King of Pop’, which artist released the album Thriller, which went on to be the bestselling album of all time?",
            "options": [
                "Prince",
                "Michael Jackson",
                "Madonna",
                "Witney Huston"
            ],
            "correct": "Michael Jackson"
        },
        {
            "id": "29",
            "question": "Which famous US singer was born in Tupelo, Mississippi in 1935 and died aged in 1977 in Graceland, Tennessee?",
            "options": [
                "Elvis",
                "Prince",
                "Andre",
                "James Brown"
            ],
            "correct": "Elvis"
        },
        {
            "id": "30",
            "question": "What is the name of the royal singer who turned the rain purple?",
            "options": [
                "James Brown",
                "Prince",
                "Elvis",
                "Michael Jackson"
            ],
            "correct": "Prince"
        },
        {
            "id": "31",
            "question": "La Louvre and Musee D’Orsay are famous museums in which city?",
            "options": [
                "Paris",
                "Lile",
                "Rome",
                "Eibar"
            ],
            "correct": "Paris"
        },
        {
            "id": "32",
            "question": "Acquired by Disney from this famous George for $4 billion in 2012, was which film production house? ",
            "options": [
                "Lucasfilm",
                "justfilm",
                "thrillerfilm",
                "johnfilm"
            ],
            "correct": "Lucasfilm"
        },
        {
            "id": "33",
            "question": "In beer, what does IPA stand for?",
            "options": [
                "Indian Pale All",
                "Indian Pale Ale",
                "Ideal Pale Ale",
                "Indian Part Ale"
            ],
            "correct": "Indian Pale Ale"
        },
        {
            "id": "34",
            "question": "Vanilla is native to which country?",
            "options": [
                "Madagascar",
                "Fuji",
                "Jamiaca",
                "Mexico"
            ],
            "correct": "Madagascar"
        },
        {
            "id": "35",
            "question": "What coloured vegetable is now mainly orange but can also be purple and yellow?",
            "options": [
                "Banana",
                "Orange",
                "Carrots",
                "Pineapple"
            ],
            "correct": "Carrots"
        },
        {
            "id": "36",
            "question": "What is the main ingredient of bread?",
            "options": [
                "Sugar",
                "Flour",
                "Egg",
                "Salt"
            ],
            "correct": "Flour"
        },
        {
            "id": "37",
            "question": "In general, roughly how many months does a human pregnancy last?",
            "options": [
                "9 months",
                "7 months",
                "8 months",
                "10 months"
            ],
            "correct": "9 months"
        },
        {
            "id": "38",
            "question": "What is the largest mammal currently inhabiting the earth?",
            "options": [
                "Shark",
                "Blue Whale",
                "Elephant",
                "Dragon"
            ],
            "correct": "Blue Whale"
        },
        {
            "id": "39",
            "question": " Often described as the longest river on earth, on which continent would you find the Nile?",
            "options": [
                "America",
                "Asia",
                "Africa",
                "North America"
            ],
            "correct": "Africa"
        },
        {
            "id": "40",
            "question": "Deciduous trees lose their leaves at certain times of the year. What is the name of trees that don’t?",
            "options": [
                "Coniferous or Evergreen",
                "Coniferous",
                "Evergreen",
                "None"
            ],
            "correct": "Coniferous or Evergreen"
        },
        {
            "id": "41",
            "question": "What is the largest land animal to roam the planet?",
            "options": [
                "The Asian Elephant",
                "The American Elephant",
                "The European Elephant",
                "The African Elephant"
            ],
            "correct": "The African Elephant"
        },
        {
            "id": "42",
            "question": "What is the name of the rainforest that is synonymous with Brazil?",
            "options": [
                "Amazon",
                "Zulu",
                "Brasile",
                "Coritiba"
            ],
            "correct": "Amazon"
        },
        {
            "id": "43",
            "question": "In which circle are you most likely to find Polar bears?",
            "options": [
                "Arctic Circle",
                "Alantic",
                "Pacific",
                "Galaxy"
            ],
            "correct": "Arctic Circle"
        },
        {
            "id": "44",
            "question": "According to the famous saying, how many lives does a cat have?",
            "options": [
                "8",
                "3",
                "5",
                "9"
            ],
            "correct": "9"
        },
        {
            "id": "45",
            "question": "What bird is famous for being pink?",
            "options": [
                "Flamingo",
                "Parot",
                "Camelon Bird",
                "Junk Bird"
            ],
            "correct": "Flamingo"
        },
        {
            "id": "46",
            "question": "What elements make up water?",
            "options": [
                "Air and Hydrogen",
                "Oxygen and Air",
                "Oxygen and Hydrogen",
                "Chlorine and Hydrogen"
            ],
            "correct": "Oxygen and Hydrogen"
        },
        {
            "id": "47",
            "question": "What double b is a common school equipment used for heating science experiments?",
            "options": [
                "Bunsen Burner",
                "Buna Burner",
                "Best Burner",
                "B Burner"
            ],
            "correct": "Bunsen Burner"
        },
        {
            "id": "48",
            "question": "True or False: Venus is the closest planet to Earth?",
            "options": [
                "None",
                "True",
                "False",
                "I dont Know"
            ],
            "correct": "True"
        },
        {
            "id": "49",
            "question": "The gaseous elements helium, neon, argon, krypton, xenon, and radon are better known as what?",
            "options": [
                "The oil Gases",
                "The Metals",
                "The Noble Gases",
                "The Inert Gases"
            ],
            "correct": "The Noble Gases"
        },
        {
            "id": "50",
            "question": "What is the simple name for molten rock that erupts from a volcano?",
            "options": [
                "Lava",
                "Fire",
                "Liquid Fire",
                "Algae"
            ],
            "correct": "Lava"
        },
        {
            "id": "51",
            "question": "Appropriately, what is the name of Saturn’s largest moon?",
            "options": [
                "Tanus",
                "Titan",
                "Sitan",
                "Mitan"
            ],
            "correct": "Titan"
        },
        {
            "id": "52",
            "question": "Which scientist came up with the theory of E=MC2?",
            "options": [
                "Newton",
                "Archimedes",
                "Albert Einstein",
                "Henry Ford"
            ],
            "correct": "Albert Einstein"
        },
        {
            "id": "53",
            "question": "What oath is taken by doctors and named after an Ancient Greek physician?",
            "options": [
                "Nepocratic",
                "Euphoppocratic",
                "Hippocratic",
                "Dempocratic"
            ],
            "correct": "Hippocratic"
        },
        {
            "id": "54",
            "question": "Who was the first black president of the United States of America?",
            "options": [
                "Martin Luther King",
                "Opra Winfred",
                "Malcom X",
                "Barak Obama"
            ],
            "correct": "Barak Obama"
        },
        {
            "id": "55",
            "question": "Who had an affair in the White House with Monica Lewinski?",
            "options": [
                "Bill Clinton",
                "George Washington",
                "Joe Biden",
                "Donal Trump"
            ],
            "correct": "Bill Clinton"
        }
    ]
}